What I want to do in this video is talk about an alternative to CSS and JS
在本视频中 我要讨论的是 react-native
that react-native provides you using the StyleSheet.create API,
借助 StyleSheet.create API 提供的 CSS 和 JS 替代方式
and that is a library called styled-components.
它是一个叫做 styled-components 的库
Now, we're not going to use this throughout the course,
在这门课程中 我们不会用到该库
but I think it's interesting to know and be aware of it,
但是我觉得有必要了解该库
because it is starting to change the game a little bit as far as styling components goes.
它在设定组件样式方面提供了不同的方式
So what you need to do before you
如果你想了解该库
actually use this, is if you want to play around with it,
在使用之前
go ahead and NPM or Yarn add styled-components.
先运行 NPM 或 Yarn add styled-components
And then, you will be able to do something like this,
然后 你将能够
where you can import styled from styled-components,
从 styled-components 导入 styled
and on react-native, go ahead and do /native.
它位于 react-native 上 因此输入 /native
Now, we have this styled object.
现在我们拥有了这个 styled 对象
The whole idea of styled-components is that
styled-components 的作用是
your styles should really be a first class citizen of your component.
让样式成为组件中的第一类公民
We've talked a little bit about that,
对此我们已经讨论过
but just as your component has state,
因为组件具有状态
your component should also have styles kind of captured inside of it.
因此还应该包含样式
So, notice here what we have,
这里是一个
is we have this view with this container style,
具有 container 样式的 View
which is just centering everything,
该样式让一切都居中
and then we have this text.
然后是这个 Text
What if, instead of adding styles like this,
如果我们不像这样添加样式
what if we actually made a component where these styles were built into it?
而是构建一个组件并内置这些样式呢？
That's really the whole idea of styled-components.
这就是 styled-components 的主要作用
So what I want to do up here is let's create something called center view,
我们在这里创建一个组件 叫做 centerView
and then what we're going to do is we're going to call styled.View,
然后调用 styled.View
and then what we're going to do is there is
这里有一个小小的 Tab 模板字面量
this little tag template literal thing right here with these back ticks.
显示为反引号
This is actually an ES6 feature,
这实际上是 ES6 功能
and what it allows us to do is now,
它使我们能够直接在这里编写真正的 CSS
instead of writing our styles and Javascript with these objects,
而不是使用这些对象
we can actually just write kind of real CSS in here.
编写样式和 Javascript
What I'm going to do is we will say flex:1 align-items center,
输入 flex: 1 align-items: center
notice that's, shouldn't be using commas,
注意 不应该使用逗号
and I'm not camelcasing anything because we're just writing this as if it is normal CSS.
也没有应用任何骆驼拼写法 因为我们就像对待普通 CSS 一样
So we're going to say, justify-content center,
输入 justify-content: center
and then we will give it a background of 333.
然后输入 background: #333
So now, center view is going to just be a react-native view component,
现在 CenterView 将是一个 react-native view 组件
but now these styles are going to be built into it.
但是这些样式是内置样式
So now, instead of saying style=styles.container,
我们可以将 style={styles.container”
we can actually just render a centerview,
改为直接渲染 CenterView
which allows us to get rid of these styles down here.
这样就可以删掉下面的样式
And now when we refresh our app,
刷新下应用
what we'll see is everything is the exact same because
一切都没变
this component just has these styles built into it.
因为该组件内置了这些样式
Let's take this a step further.
我们再进一步修改下
We can come in here and we can say,
转到这里
WelcomeText is going to be style.Text,
输入 WelcomeText = style.Text`
and then back ticks.
末尾是反引号
And then now, let's go ahead and transform this up
将这部分内容转移到这里
to here so we will say color is going to be white,
输入 color: white
and let's give it a font-size of 20 as well.
font-size 设为 20
And so now, instead of having this text,
现在我们可以将这个 Text
we can come in here and we can say centerview,
改为 CenterView
except we want to say,
不过我们要输入的是
WelcomeText, and down here,
&lt;WelcomeText&gt;
we will close WelcomeText.
然后在这里输入 &lt;/WelcomeText&gt;
And now, we can just say,
在这里输入 Hello
Hello, and everything is the same,
一切都没变
just so I can prove this is different.
将 Hello 改为 Different! 表示是另一种形式
There we go. So you'll notice the styling is just built in to the component itself.
样式是内置在组件本身里的
Let's take this one step further.
我们再进一步修改下
Say we had a button that we wanted to
假设我们想要使用一个按钮
use and we wanted to add these styles to the button.
并且想要向按钮上添加这些样式
What we can do is let's say,
我们可以输入 WelcomeBtn
WelcomeBtn, and we can use styled.TouchableOpacity.
并且可以使用 styled.TouchableOpacity
And then this button is going to have a few different properties on it.
该按钮将具有几个不同的属性
We'll say, width is 100 pixels,
width 为 100px
height is going to be 50 pixels, backgrounds is red.
height 为 50px background 为 red
Notice, this is just like we're typing CSS here so if you have
注意 这里相当于输入 CSS 代码
been hating on CSS and JS this whole time,
如果你一直都很讨厌 CSS 和 JS
you should be very happy with styled-components and you can
则应该非常喜欢 styled-components
actually go ahead and use styled-components throughout the rest of the course.
实际上你可以在这门课程的后续阶段一直使用 styled-components
I won't, but if you want to,
但是我不会的
by all means, you will learn a lot doing it.
如果你想这样的话 将会学到很多知识
Then we have alignItems center as well.
然后输入 align-items: center
S now, what I want to do is let's go ahead and render our WelcomeBtn and so now,
渲染 WelcomeBtn
the question is what do I do,
现在的问题是 如果操作
where do I add the onPress prop?
在何处添加 onPress 属性？
Well, we can do that, just on the component itself.
我们可以直接在组件本身上添加该属性
Any props that you pass to a styled-component is
传递给 styled-component 的任何属性
just going to be passed through to the real component.
都将传递给真正的组件
So in here, what we will say is,
因此 在这里
we will alert Hello,
输入 alert(‘Hello!’)
and then let's say, PUSH ME.
然后输入 PUSH ME
So if everything is working correctly, there we go.
看看一切是否正常
When we push, notice we get Hello.
当我们点击按钮时 出现了 Hello
But now, just one last change.
再进行最后一项更改
Instead of using the text component,
我们不再使用这个 Text 组件
let's just go ahead and reuse our WelcomeText component that we built earlier up here,
而是重复使用之前构建的 WelcomeText 组件
so that we can get these styles and we will just say,
以便获取这些样式
PUSH ME, and there we go.
然后输入 Push me
So what we've done is we've taken this idea of adding
刚刚这些修改的作用是
CSS into our components one step further and now,
进一步将 CSS 添加到组件中
they're actually built into the components themselves.
现在它们已经内置到组件本身中了
So if you haven't looked at either styled-components, glamorous,
如果你没有见过 styled-components、glamorous,
they're all really similar,
其实它们很相似
definitely check it out because it's a really interesting space right now.
请务必了解下这些库 因为它们现在很热门